Do you want subtitles for any video?
-=[ ai.OpenSubtitles.com ]=-
[wind whistling]
-[leaves rustling]
-[trees creaking]
[electricity humming]
[birds chirping]
[students chattering]
[bus driver] Stay seated.
Don't do that please.
Give it up. Thank you.
[brakes squealing]
See you.
-[student] Thank you.
-You're welcome. Have a good day.
963 to Base.
Clifton Road dropped. Over.
[dispatcher] Copy that. 963.
[chattering continues]
[students chanting]
Fight! Fight!
Bye. Thanks.
You're welcome.
[door closes]
[engine revs]
[student laughs]
Hey. Quit messing with
the windows please.
963 to Base.
All kids dropped. Over.
[dispatcher] Copy that. 963.
[reporter] Meanwhile. the
Mavericks broke their losing streak
with a resounding win
over the Wizards. 119-100.
Weather today.
sunny. dry and windy.
Still no sign of an end
to this record dry spell.
Day 210 without a drop of rain.
And don't forget.
there's a Red Flag Wildfire
Warning in effect for Butte County
and surrounding
areas through Friday.
with the possibility
of electrical shutoffs.
Looking ahead. you guessed it.
even more dry and windy weather
in store tomorrow with gusts anywhere
from 60 to 80 miles per hour.
In local news.
after going eight...
Hey. what do I need for
Billie Park? Who can I get?
[worker] Try 190.
Great.
-This is Base. You there. Mack?
-What do you need?
Yeah. Can you do the Billie Park
pickup today? Phil's bailed.
-[Mack] No problem. Chief.
-Thank you so much.
Base clear. Hey. Kevin.
-Yeah?
-Got those time sheets for me?
[inhales deeply] No. I'll. uh... I'll
make sure to bring 'em in tomorrow.
Okay. And the foreman says
you're behind on maintenance.
That's your responsibility.
-Yeah?
-Copy that.
[Ruby] Hi there. This is Ruby at
the Unified Transportation District.
Yeah.
[Kevin clears throat] Hey. boss.
Yeah. Just a sec.
Hey there. It's Ruby
down at the bus yard.
Uh. I was just wondering if you knew
anything about the PG&E shutoffs.
We got a Red Flag Warning. so I just need
to know if the schools are gonna close.
Yeah. I'll hold.
-What's up? Mmm.
-About those additional shifts.
Um... [stammers] ...I could
sure use the extra this month.
Uh. I've got my dad's medical
bills. I'm taking care of my mom.
My ex is home.
Uh. so it's a bit
of a sticky time.
Yeah. I just don't have
anything for you. Kevin.
[stammers] Well. boss. when
I signed up. you said...
I said maybe. yeah?
And people that have been here
longer. the guys that have seniority.
-they get first pick of overtime shifts.
-Hey. buddy. Hurry it up.
-[Kevin] Mind your business. old man.
-[Ruby] Hey.
If anything comes up.
I'll let you know.
Do you copy?
Copy.
-I'm not staying on the line.
-[handset settles in cradle]
Richard. I am so sorry.
[Richard] It's okay.
["Broken Halos"
playing on radio]
[seat belt clicks]
[radio turns off]
[phone ringing]
[sighs]
-Yeah.
-[on phone] Hey. Kevin. It's Dr. Everett.
We got Elvis's X-rays back.
-Bad news. I'm afraid.
-[sighs]
-His cancer has spread.
I think it's time.
[Kevin] All right. doc. I'll... I'll
bring him by tonight. Thank you.
[softly] Hey. bud.
How you doing?
Come here. Come here. buddy.
Come here.
Come here. Come here.
come here. come here.
Hop up.
-I got ya. I got ya. I got ya.
-[Elvis whines]
[groans]
[exhales deeply] You want
a burger for dinner. buddy?
Huh?
[whispering] I got you. buddy.
[chattering on TV]
-Hey. Ma.
-Hey. Kevin.
-There you go. buddy.
-[Elvis whines]
There you go.
Shaun's home.
-[Kevin] Home?
-[mother] He said he was sick.
And you believed him?
All I need is the school
board on my ass now.
[mother] You okay?
Struggling. Ma.
I can't seem to catch a break.
[mother] So. what. back to Reno?
[Kevin] No.
I just...
I just can't make it here.
Well. you know your dad did.
[Kevin] Yeah. Well.
I'm not him. remember?
[footsteps approaching]
School's important. bud.
[Shaun] Wasn't important to you.
[shushes]
Lay down.
Buddy... [stammers]
...that's different.
-[Shaun] Dropped out. yeah?
-[Kevin sighing] Yeah. I did.
We got pregnant.
I ha... I had to.
-So it's my fault then?
-No.
[chuckles] It's not
your fault. bud.
[stammers] I just... I don't
want you making my mistakes.
That... Tha-That's all.
Come on. U-Unpack your bags. Put
your stuff in a proper drawer.
I'm off this Saturday.
You and I can do
something this weekend.
I'm good.
I don't feel well.
Talk to me. buddy.
Talk to me.
[rock music playing on speaker]
You think I wanna be here? Huh?
You think I wanna be here
taking care of your grandma?
All right. But you... Don't...
Hey. Listen to me. I don't
have a choice. You do.
Dad. it's not fair that
I have to change my life.
Grow up!
Wait till you gotta pay bills!
Wait till you got a job that's
a dead-end motherfucker.
that doesn't pay.
and you can't quit.
You know what it's like to
not have some pity party?
You know what it's like not
-to have something to look forward to?
-Yeah. I do.
-Well. how the fuck do you know?
-I know because of you.
[music continues]
This is my fault now?
Of course it's not. Dad.
Never is.
You know. I fucking hate you.
I wish you were dead!
[dog whimpers]
[exhales deeply]
Okay. buddy.
[Elvis whines]
-Good boy.
-[veterinarian] You had him long?
Since he was a puppy.
-[veterinarian] Do you wanna hold him?
-[Kevin] Yeah.
It's okay. buddy.
[sighs] It's okay. buddy.
It's okay.
[whispers] It's okay. buddy.
[wind whistling]
[metal creaking]
[electricity humming]
[clattering. creaking]
[reporter] ...weather now. and
it's another dry and windy day
in Paradise with gusts in the
canyon up to 80 miles per hour.
That Red Flag Wildfire Warning is still
in effect. so be careful out there.
and be sure to report any signs
of smoke or fire immediately.
Looking at tomorrow...
[wind whistling]
[Ruby] Hey. guys. We got
a couple of downed trees
in these winds on Roe Road.
That's Roe Road. so just...
Watch out for power lines too.
All right. Base out.
-Hey. Kevin.
-Hey. boss.
[Ruby] Mechanic's
in this morning.
so I want you to get 963
serviced when you get back.
Well past three K limit.
I want you to stick around.
watch him do his checks.
It's gonna take a couple hours.
but it's stuff you gotta know.
-All right?
-Copy that. boss.
There's yesterday's time sheet.
Thank you. sir.
Pleasure doing business.
[door opens]
[engine starts]
-[dispatcher] Fire and Rescue.
-[driver] Yeah. Hey.
I'm out on Highway 70
by the Pulga Bridge.
Looks like some sort of a grass
fire on the west side of the canyon.
and it's really
blowing out here.
Okay. Highway 70
near Pulga Bridge.
Hold on one moment for me. sir.
-[chattering on radio]
-[typing]
Okay. I think I see
what you're seeing.
Uh. thank you for the report. We will
get the fire department on the way. okay?
[firefighter] He's got... He's
got arms the size of your thighs.
He's-He's like this.
[firefighters laughing]
[alarm blares]
[dispatcher] Jarbo
Gap. Vegetation fire.
Engine 2161. Engine 2176.
reported vegetation fire
at Highway 70 near
the Pulga Bridge.
Please respond.
Oroville. Engine 2161.
Engine 2176 responding.
[chattering]
[firefighter 1] Up. Simbas!
Let's go. we got work...
Let's go. Let's go. Let's go.
[firefighter 2] Five more
minutes. I'd have breakfast.
[engine starts]
[siren wailing]
[students chattering]
-[student] Good Morning.
-Morning.
-[student 2] Good Morning.
-[student 3] Morning.
-[siren wailing]
-[chattering on radio]
Okay. Come on. Clear.
[siren wailing]
It's gotta be a failed cable.
Right underneath those towers.
You know. getting to it
is gonna be the problem.
What about there?
Can we even get
our rigs in there?
It's tight. but
let's give it a shot.
All right. Let's back 'em up!
-[firefighter 1] Let's move.
-[firefighter 2] Go.
[phone ringing]
[Kevin] Can't talk right now.
Ma. I'll call you right back.
-[door opens]
-Okay. Let's go. Go.
[student 1] See you later.
-[student 2] Thank you.
-Bye.
-[student 3] Thank you.
-[student 4] Bye.
-[ringing continues]
-[student 5] Uh-huh. see ya.
-[student 6] Thank you. Have a great day.
-Have a good day.
[firefighter] Watch out on this
side. The road can't take the weight.
Yeah. I see that.
2176. 2161.
Just be careful on the
right. Looks a little shaky.
Copy that. cap.
[wind whistling]
[captain] All right.
Heavy smoke ahead.
[firefighter 2] Don't
know about this.
[captain] Let's stick with it.
Let's knock this thing out
before it becomes something.
[grunts] Geez.
[phone ringing]
Yeah. Ma.
[on phone] I've been trying
to get a hold of you.
Shaun's throwing up.
He's really not well.
Shit.
Um. does he have a fever?
I don't know. He's
in the bathroom.
[Ruby] 963. Base
calling. Do you read?
Ha-Hang on a second. Ma.
Uh. Base. this is 963.
[Ruby] Have you
completed drop-off yet?
[Kevin] Yes. boss.
Drop-off complete.
[Ruby] Bring her on in then.
The mechanic's waiting for you.
Okay. Just need
to fuel up first.
You're meant to do that
before pickup. 963.
[Kevin] Copy that. boss.
Doing the best I can.
I will be in as soon
as I fuel up. okay?
963 out.
Yeah. Ma. Uh. did you.
uh. take his temperature?
[mother] I'm looking
for the thermometer.
It should be in the
first aid kit. Um...
It's not there.
[Kevin] How about under the
kitchen sink? Try there. Ma.
I've gotta pull in to fuel up.
-I'll call you right back. okay?
-[mother] Okay.
[Kevin] Come on. come on.
come on. come on. come on.
[inhales sharply] Come on.
All right. I-I got it. I got it.
-Oroville. Engine 2161.
-[dispatcher] Oroville.
I got a visual.
Blowing southwest
under the power lines.
Gotta be about 100 acres.
Hey. I don't know about this.
We don't have an escape route.
[captain] We're close.
Let's stick with it.
[firefighter] Look at it. cap.
There's no way we're getting up there.
[captain grunts]
We gotta turn around.
Let's find an
alternative strike point.
This route's no good.
Cap. come on.
Okay.
Oroville. Engine 2161.
[dispatcher] 2161.
Oroville. Copy.
We can't reach it down
here. It's too dangerous.
We're gonna head back up the ridge and
see if we can find a new strike point.
[dispatcher] Copy that. ICP is being
established at Scooter's on Highway 70.
Resources are out.
[horn honks]
Come on.
Let's go!
[dispatcher] For Division 2102.
Engine 2186. Engine
2182. Engine 2162.
Transport 2140. Transport 2142. Butte
crew 1. Butte crew 2. Butte crew 3.
vegetation fire reported in
the area of Camp Creek Road.
Respond to staging at
Scooter's on Highway 70.
[officer] Yes. keep it coming.
[siren wailing]
[chattering]
-Okay. what have we got?
-[firefighter] Okay.
Fire started about
right here. all right?
We think it's about two to three hundred
acres. so it's sitting about like that.
A really strong east wind
pushed it down canyon.
The Jarbo Gap engines tried to
make access across Camp Creek Road.
They couldn't do it. Just
got too narrow. too steep.
They backed out.
They are now coming
up over the ridge.
and they're trying to make
access down from the top.
Have any other engines deployed?
Yeah. [stammers] We got five
additional strike teams en route.
[chief] Copy that. Any
communities threatened?
Yeah. We got Pulga a mile west.
This is an old gold rush
post. It's uninhabited.
And then we got Concow.
Okay. so this is a good couple miles
away. It's well clear of the fire.
Uh. trailers and cabins
mostly. Eight hundred people.
Retirees. pot smokers.
homesteaders. that kind of thing.
[chief] Let's issue an
evac warning just in case.
-[firefighter 2] Okay.
-[chief] What about Paradise?
[firefighter 1] Chief. it's eight miles
away on the other side of the canyon.
Population's about 27.000.
I don't think it's an
issue. They should be fine.
[phone ringing]
-Yeah.
-[mother] Uh...
-Huh?
-One.
-One what?
-Uh... [stammers] ...11.
No. No. no. no. Look. it can't
be 111. No. that's impossible.
If it was 111. he'd be dead.
-Pump 1.
-Pump number?
[mother] I can't read these
numbers. They're so tiny.
[Kevin] Have Shaun
read it for you.
-[mother] He's. uh...
-Shaun. are you there?
-...101.
-Shaun. get on the phone. will ya?
So. he-he's got a temperature.
He doesn't want to talk. Kevin.
He-he says he'll
speak to you later.
-He probably just needs his mom.
-I'm sure he does need his mom. huh?
-He's sick. but he's here with his dad.
-[fire truck horn blares]
He's got me. and he's got you.
Listen. Ma. I can't talk right now.
I gotta get the bus to the depot.
I'll swing by the drugstore.
get Shaun some medicine.
I'll be home as soon as
I can after work. okay?
[dispatcher] Camp IC. Oroville.
We're getting unconfirmed reports
of another fire in that area.
Oroville. Camp IC. Go
ahead. What's its location?
Camp IC. Oroville. We're unsure.
There's a lot of smoke in the area.
and we have a couple cameras down.
but I believe it to be off
Rim Road. north of Concow.
Uh. Oroville. Camp IC copies.
What do you think? That's
a second start or a spot?
[firefighter 1] We're
three miles away.
I don't know how the heck
that would be a spot fire.
That's a long ways from
the-the original fire.
[firefighter 2] Okay.
-I think we've got two fires.
-Camp IC. we received a call
from PG&E. They advised
of a power outage
approximately ten minutes ago
in the Rim Road area of Concow.
-I believe this...
-So it was a power line then.
...is gonna be related to your second start.
There are power lines down in that area.
The PG&E linemen are here.
Do you want them to wait?
-No. I wanna talk to them.
-Okay.
The hell are you guys
doing? I got two fires now.
I need all your lines
in the area shut down.
right away. before I
get any more fires.
We had Red Flag Warnings last
night. You guys knew about this.
Why didn't you
shut it down then?
Look. we'll get our people down
to the substation to shut it down.
We'll get up to the transmission
tower to secure the downed lines.
I got two fires now.
It's on your headquarters. It wasn't your
fault. but let's get this taken care of.
Messina. Messina.
Send five additional strike
teams to this new start.
[lieutenant] Chief. are you
copying this priority traffic?
[person on radio] Camp IC.
Utility 2136. Priority traffic.
Utility 2136. Camp IC. Go ahead.
This is Engineer
Hopkins on Utility 2136.
I'm going off duty
out in Concow.
We've got a serious situation
developing. be advised.
Heavy smoke and embers
blowing in out here.
-Are you sure about that? In Concow?
-Concow?
[Hopkins] That's affirmative.
I'm driving through it now.
Uh. we've got embers
falling around structures.
It's jumped the fucking box.
[siren wailing]
Correction. We've
got a spot fire.
[people screaming]
Correction. Multiple spots.
I count one. two.
three. big ones.
Rapid rate of spread.
I'm losing visibility fast.
That's a hell of a
distance for a spread.
Gotta be at least five miles.
You think it's another
set of power lines?
No. no. no. I guarantee the
power's already off up in Concow.
[firefighter] I mean. that's
a lot of distance covered.
Messina.
Listen to me. It's one fire.
-[firefighter] No. No. that...
-It's one fire.
No. that would be impossible
for it to move that way.
-All one damn fire.
-[firefighter 2] If we got one fire.
you're looking at a
perimeter about... like that.
Okay. Let's send
resources to Concow.
Air tankers. engines.
Give him what he needs.
-[firefighter 2] Tankers. Yeah.
-Copy. You got that?
Okay. So. if we've
got fire in Concow.
we have to change that
evac warning to an order.
-Do it.
-Copy.
New containment line
is Jordan Hill Road.
[Ruby] All drivers.
this is Base. Listen up.
Uh. well. I guess today's
a real special day
because we just saw that Cal
Fire's got a fire up by Concow.
So. uh. y'all know the drill.
Just stay off the radio. and be
listening for code reds. okay?
[Ruby] 963. Base
call. You on your way?
Uh. Base. this is 963.
Uh. ETA 15 minutes. boss.
I've got one more quick
stop I gotta make.
[Ruby] Kevin. you need to
get bus 963 into the garage.
or you're gonna miss
your afternoon route.
I told you. it's gonna
take at least two hours.
Understood. boss. Uh. I've got a
bit of a family situation. okay?
[Ruby] Kevin. I'm
not interested. okay?
I need you to get the bus back here now.
The mechanic can't wait around all day.
Copy that. boss. I'll be
there as soon as I can. Over.
[fire truck horn blares]
[siren wailing]
-Everyone. evacuate! Let's go!
-[person] Help!
-Go get in that truck. okay?
-[person 2 crying]
Everyone. evacuate!
Let's go!
Leave everything. Leave
that. Leave everything.
Get in the car now!
-Hey. is there anyone else inside?
-[person 3] No.
[Hopkins] Anyone inside?
[person 4] Come
on. baby. Let's go.
[Hopkins] Fire department!
[grunts] Guys. let's go.
Leave your bags.
Leave your bags!
-[people clamoring. screaming]
-Everyone. evacuate!
-[child crying] Mommy!
-Leave it.
-We gotta go. Come on!
-No!
[Hopkins] I said get her
in the car now. Let's go.
-Do you have a car?
-[person 5] No.
Go get in that white truck. Hurry
up. Let's go. Hold on tight.
Go!
[people screaming]
IC. Utility 2136.
Be advised. we need medics
for multiple burn injuries.
I'm starting a convoy.
We're heading out
on Concow Road.
Follow me! Stay close!
Everyone. follow each other!
Everyone. hang on. okay?
-Let's go.
-[engine revs]
[horns honking]
-Hello?
-[clerk] Do you have any questions
-about...
-Hello?
[clerk] I'll be with
you in a moment.
[Kevin] Okay.
-Uh...
-Sounds good. And they are chewable.
You can eat that.
-That I don't think is a good idea.
-[sighs]
Okay.
Ma'am. my son. uh... [stammers] He's
got a fever. and he's throwing up.
I was on the phone.
-Uh. your son. how old is he?
-Sure.
Fourteen.
-Um. does he have any allergies?
-He's 15. actually.
Yeah. He's 15. No. uh...
-[stammers] I don't know.
-Food intolerances or anything like that?
[stammers] I don't think so. No.
Whatever the standard thing is
for-for-for fever and throwing up.
Okay. Sounds like
-Tylenol would be your best bet.
-Yeah.
Great. Thank you.
[clerk] Great. These
are going for $7.25.
-[Kevin] Okay. All right.
-[phone ringing]
-I'll be right there. Linda.
-Would you like a bag?
[Kevin] No. That's good.
You can keep the change.
S-Sir. I can...
-Yeah. Go ahead. Huh? No.
-[Linda] What's going on. Kevin?
Shaun's been messaging.
Says he wants to come home.
-No.
-He says he wants me to come get him.
-No. That... That's ridiculous.
-Well. he sounds upset.
-What happened?
-Nothing.
We had a little misunderstanding.
I thought he was cutting class.
-Well. was he?
-[pants] Was he what?
-Was he cutting class?
-No.
[exhales deeply] It was my mistake.
He's actually got a stomach flu.
But look. I just picked up some
Tylenol. so everything's fine.
It's not fine. Kevin. Not if he's
ill and saying he wants to come home.
I don't have time for
this right now. Linda.
You hear me? I'm already late to get
the bus to the depot for maintenance.
And you think I got time?
I'm working too. you know?
And Pete and I are supposed to
be going to Colorado tonight.
-Tonight?
-Yes. tonight.
I told you.
My bad. Listen. Linda. I'm
gonna have to call you back.
963 to Base.
Okay. 963. Base call.
You on your way. Kevin?
[Kevin] Are there any
updates on that fire?
Because I'm up here in Magalia. and
I... and I can see the smoke column
o-over the canyon. okay?
-And it's blowing right at us.
-Kevin. there are no updates.
Cal Fire's all over it. okay?
Now. get that bus back here now.
I've already asked you three times.
Now. get back here or you
can look for another job.
Base clear.
Copy that. boss. On my way in.
[pilot] Camp IC.
Camp Air Attack.
Tankers inbound.
ETA four minutes.
[dispatcher] Copy.
Engines responding.
En route to Concow reservoir. heading
southbound on Jordan Hill Road.
[dispatcher 2] Copy.
Uh. what's the ETA
on those engines?
The Paradise engines
are 18 minutes out.
Copy that. Utility 2136.
Air Attack is inbound.
18 minutes on those engines.
Negative! That's too long. We're
gonna get burned over here.
Jesus!
-[sobs]
-Just hang on. guys.
[pilot] Camp Air Attack. Air tankers
inbound. retardant drop at the head.
Camp IC. Camp Air Attack.
We're having problems hitting
the targets with these winds.
Air Attack. Camp IC. I need
you to try a second pass.
[firefighter] Chief. the Paradise
engines are 15 minutes out from Concow.
Okay. Oroville. Camp IC.
[dispatcher] Camp IC.
Oroville. Go ahead.
Uh. Oroville. Camp IC requesting ten
air tankers. six Type 1 helicopters.
one lead plane and 25 additional
engines immediately to Concow.
[dispatcher] Camp
IC. Oroville copies.
All county aircraft.
ten tankers.
six Type 1 copters. 25
additional engines immediately.
[firefighter 2] Oroville. I copy.
Moving resources to Concow now.
Utility 2136. can you
get onto Camelot Road?
[Hopkins] Negative. The fire's
blocked it. I'm cut off.
This thing is going
to burn over them.
-Get 'em to the bridge.
-Hoffman Bridge?
-Get 'em to Hoffman Bridge.
-That's the best place.
Utility 2136. can you reach Hoffman
Bridge and shelter in the water?
[Hopkins] Camp IC. I'll try.
-[passengers crying]
-All right. listen up!
As soon as I stop the
truck. you're gonna get out.
you're gonna run into the creek!
As soon as you get in the creek.
cover your mouth. protect your airway.
Feet to the fire. okay?
Everyone understand?
[siren wailing]
-All right. let's go!
-[passengers clamoring]
[person whimpers. exclaims]
-Go! Get in the water now!
-[person wailing]
Into the water! Let's go!
Hang on! Into the water!
Utility 2136.
multiple residents taking
shelter in the creek!
[screaming]
-[grunts]
-Oh. my God! [screams]
[grunts] Goddamn it!
Get as far out as you can!
Come on!
Utility 2136...
burn over imminent!
What's the status
on our support?
[chief] Utility 2136. copy that. Air
Attack are making their second pass.
Engines are ten minutes out.
[pilot] Camp IC.
Camp Air Attack.
Air tankers inbound now.
[chief] Uh. Air
Attack. Camp IC copies.
[people clamoring]
[Hopkins] Come on. Come on!
Keep calm!
[firefighter] Camp
IC. Engine 2182.
We've got multiple obstacles in
the roadway. We can't get through.
The road is blocked.
Repeating. access is
completely blocked.
[chief] Air Attack. Camp IC.
give me an update on that drop.
[pilot] Camp IC.
Camp Air Attack.
No impact with the
drop. No impact at all.
Damn it. where are
those Paradise engines?
[firefighter] I just got word
they're not gonna make it through.
They're stuck. They're
not gonna make it.
[Hopkins] Stay
together! It's coming!
-[people whimpering]
-Stay calm! We'll make it through!
Heads down!
Burnover! Burnover! Burnover!
[people screaming]
Utility 2136.
what's your status?
Utility 2136. do you copy?
-[firefighter 2] Answer the radio.
-Come on. Come on.
Utility 2136. do you copy?
[firefighter 2] It's not good.
[Hopkins] Initial
wave has passed.
We're sheltering in the creek.
We got multiple burn injuries.
and we need help now!
Utility 2136. copy that.
Hold your position.
We'll get medics in and dozers
inbound to clear an evac path.
[Hopkins] You don't understand!
Extreme fire behavior.
Critical rate of spread.
heading west towards Paradise!
[sighs]
[fire crackling]
-[crows cawing]
-Whoa!
[sirens wailing]
[line ringing]
Shaun.
Hey. it's me. Dad. Listen. um...
I'm sorry about last night.
All right. [stutters] I'm
sorry you're not feeling well.
[stutters] I just
picked up some medicine.
[stutters] I'll get it to you as soon
as I get home after work. All right?
Listen... [stutters] ...I
need you to do me a favor.
All right. the...
fire out in Concow.
I don't think it's
anything to worry about.
But just in case. turn on Channel
7 so you can keep an eye on it.
Okay? I don't... I don't
want Grandma to worry.
You know how she
gets worried. Huh?
All right. buddy.
[stutters] I'll
see you after work.
Hope you're feeling better.
[siren wailing]
Uh. Oroville. Camp IC. Uh.
we gotta get people moving.
Alert Town Hall.
Issue mandatory evacuation warning
for zones 3. 8. 14. East Paradise.
anything east of Pentz Road.
Estimate about 4.000 residents.
[dispatcher] Camp
IC. Oroville copies.
-Mandatory evacuation zones 3. 8. 14.
-We stay focused.
We have a plan. We stick to it.
[helicopter whirring]
[siren wailing]
[official 1] Okay. Yes.
I... I've got it. All right.
They've issued an
evacuation order.
Phone lines are down.
[town hall official 1] Come on.
All right. give me those zones.
-[town hall official 2] Uh. 3. 8 and 14.
-[typing]
-East Paradise only.
-[computer beeps]
[town hall official 1 sighs]
It won't go through.
It didn't send.
Okay. [sighs]
[sighs] Go!
[chief] Camp Air Attack. Camp IC. I
need air support in the canyon now.
We need you to buy us some time.
[firefighter] Chief. look at that
fire coming down towards Paradise.
[pilot] Camp IC.
Camp Air Attack.
We are having zero impact.
The fire is spotting onto the
western side of the canyon.
Wind speed is a real problem.
IC copies. We need
outside resources.
Requesting 50 additional
strike teams immediately.
[dispatcher] Camp
IC. Oroville copies.
That's gonna be extended. sir.
minimum two to three hours.
Chief. if-if we don't get
resources i-into Paradise now.
we're gonna lose this thing.
It's gonna be too late.
We're gonna lose
our air support.
It's too dangerous to
fly in these conditions.
There's no way they're
gonna continue in this wind.
[pilot] Camp IC. Branch
3. We're being overrun.
The fire is crossing the
canyon. We can't stop it.
Do you copy? We can't stop it.
[students clamoring]
[teacher] Okay. Mary's
class. sit down.
Class.
we don't all need to
look out the window.
It's just another brush fire.
Nothing new. Come sit down.
Take out a book.
-Do we know what we're doing?
-Still no evacuation order.
I'm not waiting.
Okay. let's just get everyone out of
here and home as quickly as we can.
Okay. I'll send an
email to parents.
If any of your students have
phones or know their numbers.
-get the parents to collect.
-Okay. but...
but some of my kids have
parents who work out of town.
and the parents will never get here in
time. What do we do about those kids?
Okay. [stutters] I'm sure they're gonna
have an alternative collection point.
So. let's just gather together the
students who can't be collected.
And I'll just keep
trying Town Hall.
[teacher] Okay. Thank you.
Okay. um...
Echo. Do you know your
mom's phone number?
-Uh-huh.
-You do?
-Great. F...
-435-232...
Okay. Hold on one second. I'm
gonna ask you to write it down.
Who else knows their mom
or dad's phone number?
[phone ringing]
-[Kevin] Yeah?
-[Linda] You said you'd call me back.
[Kevin] I'm sorry.
I got distracted.
Look. I don't want to argue.
I'm tired of the same
fight every week.
We don't need to argue. Lin.
There's nothing to argue about.
Okay. [stutters] I didn't
realize our son was sick.
It was an honest mistake. [stutters]
You don't need to get involved.
-Then why is he calling me?
-[siren wailing]
[Kevin] I don't
know! Linda. he's 15!
He got in a fight with his
dad. and he's calling his mom.
Don't make this a bigger deal than it
is. [stutters] I'm dealing with it.
[Ruby] Base to 963.
what is your location?
-Uh. 963. ETA. ten minutes.
-[horns honking]
The traffic is
backed up over here.
[Linda] Face it. Kevin.
You're just... unreliable.
No. No. [stutters] I'm not
doing this right now. Lin.
I'm not gonna sit here and go over all
the ways that I screwed up with you.
Listen. it's been tough...
lately with Dad dying.
[Linda] Don't use
your dad as an excuse.
The funeral was four months ago. and
you barely spoke to him for 20 years.
He ruined your life.
That's what you told me!
That's bullshit. Linda.
That's bullshit.
That's a low blow.
[Linda] I'm sorry.
That wasn't nice.
It's just the first weekend I've
been away with anyone since we...
You know what I mean.
[chattering on radio]
Can you turn the radio
down? I can barely hear you.
[Kevin] Turning it down.
All I'm saying is I know
it's been hard for you.
but you gotta think about Shaun.
He looks at you. and
all he sees is...
What?
What does he see
when he looks at me?
-Don't make me say it. Kevin.
-No. go ahead. say it. Say it.
-You know what I mean.
-Say it.
[sighs] There's a reason
why your life is a mess.
and Shaun doesn't
want to be with you.
I gotta go.
[sighs]
[Ruby] Base to all drivers.
We're having issues with
the comms over here.
Is everybody hearing me?
[line ringing]
Hey. hey. Shaun. Hey. it's Dad.
Listen. uh...
[stutters] I need to know
you're okay. buddy. I. uh...
Call me back if you're getting
any of these messages. please.
Okay? I gotta. um...
I gotta run... I gotta
run the bus to the depot.
Swinging by maintenance for a
couple of hours. then I'll...
[sighs]
You know what?
[stutters] I'm coming
home right now.
-You hear me. buddy?
-[engine revs]
I'm coming home right now.
[horn honks]
I got your medicine on me. I'll
be there in 20 minutes max.
[horns honking]
Hey. all drivers. this is Base.
This is an important update.
We are now evacuating
East Paradise only.
-[worker] What zones?
-[Ruby] East Paradise zones 3. 8 and 14.
That is 3. 8 and 14 only.
Any driver east of Clark
all the way to Pentz.
you need to evacuate
that area immediately.
They're worried about the fire
coming across the canyon from Concow.
So if you have any
children on board.
you need to take them west all the
way out of town to the Chico depot.
Repeat. the evacuation
muster point is Chico depot.
Base clear.
[parent] Okay. honey. Get in.
-[engine revs]
-Come on. come on. Stop!
[students chattering]
All right. let's. um...
I'll be right back.
All right. so we
got the evac order.
Apparently. their system went down.
and they weren't able to get it out.
They want every student who
hasn't already been collected
to be taken over to
Paradise Elementary.
Okay? That's the new
collection point.
That's where they're
sending all the parents.
Okay. Well. we have 23
kids without transport.
So how are we gonna
get them there?
[teacher] I can
take four in my car.
-I didn't drive. so I can't help at all.
-No. no.
[stammers] We cannot get
them there by ourselves.
We don't have enough cars.
-[principal] Yes.
-They need to send us a bus.
-Call Ruby.
-Oh. yeah. I'll call the depot.
Hi. Anna. It's. um... It's Mary.
Look. they're evacuating East
Paradise. and I can't get to Jake.
Steven's out of town for work.
And I was wondering if
you could go get him.
and then I'll just get
to you as soon as I can.
Um. okay. Thank you.
Uh. let me know that you got
this. All right? Love you. Bye.
[phone rings]
[Ruby] Unified Schools
Transportation Office.
Uh. I'm sorry. Uh. can you...
Can you speak up please?
It's the principal of Ponderosa.
Yes. ma'am.
Yes. ma'am. Yes. ma'am.
They need a bus
to take them west
to the alternative collection
point at Paradise Elementary.
Just outside the evac zone.
Do we have anybody on a route
over there? Check the route maps.
-Cesar.
-[Cesar] Yeah?
[Ruby] I need you to go out
and prep a bus just in case.
-[Cesar] All right.
-Yes. ma'am.
We are gonna get a bus
right out to you. okay?
So you just sit tight. Okay?
Thank you so much.
All right. Bye-bye.
Uh. Base to all drivers. this is
an update on that evac notice.
We have a situation.
Ponderosa Elementary.
I repeat. there's a situation
developing at Ponderosa Elementary.
There are 23 kids who are
stranded in the evacuation zone.
Their parents cannot make
it in to pick them up.
They need to be picked up
and taken to the alternative collection
point at Paradise Elementary.
Is there anybody empty and
in the area of East Paradise?
[bus driver 1] 987 to
Base. Sorry. all full.
Not reached my school yet.
[bus driver 2] 910 to
Base. Full here too. Ruby.
Ten minutes from dropping off.
Come on.
[bus driver 3] 922 to Base.
I'm en route to Chico.
I'm just passing Base.
but I can swing back.
[Ruby] No. 922.
Do not swing back.
Once you get out of
there. you get out.
Those roads are gonna get
real crazy real quick. okay?
Is there anybody in East
Paradise with an empty bus
that can go and
pick these kids up?
No. No.
[sighs]
963 to Base. I can get 'em.
Kevin. is that you?
Yeah.
Yeah. I'm still on this
side of town. Remember?
I was running late.
Yep. yep. I remember.
So. uh. we can do maintenance
another day. okay?
Listen. if you get those kids
out. you will have done well.
Okay. Kevin? You copy?
Copy that. Have them lined up.
I'm on my way.
[siren wailing]
[chattering on radio]
[chattering]
-[horns honking]
-[siren wailing]
-[horn honking]
-"And it was..."
Oh. there's the bus. Okay.
okay. okay. Stay seated.
Stay sitting please. everybody.
[honking continues]
[grunts]
[Kevin] Twenty kids for evac?
They're in there.
Around to the right.
-[Kevin] Hi.
-[Mary] Hi.
-Are you here for the kids?
-Yes. I am. Are they... Are they ready?
Um. yep. We're gathering
them up right now.
-[Kevin] Okay.
-Um. what's your name?
-Kevin. And. uh...
-Kevin. hi. I'm Mary.
-Hi. As soon as we can gather...
-Yeah. great. We are...
-We're gonna get 'em in line in a minute.
-Yeah.
These kids. their parents couldn't
make it 'cause they work too...
-Paradise Elementary. Got it.
-Right. The alternative drop-off.
Yep. Got it. Ready to go.
-Principal Hayes. Thank you for coming.
-Hi. Yep.
-Okay...
-Sooner the better.
...and we're just gonna
keep it calm for the kids.
Kids. this is our bus driver.
Kevin. Can we say hi to Kevin?
[students] Hi. Kevin.
[Mary] Can I get you
in two straight lines?
Shortest in the front.
Tallest in the back.
And Kevin is gonna drive
you to Paradise Elementary.
where your parents are
going to pick you up.
I'm gonna lead the
line. Principal.
If you could please take the back
and do a head count while we walk.
If you're ready.
raise your hand.
Let me see your
eyes. Eyes on me.
I want to see everybody's eyes.
-Are we ready?
-[students] Yes.
[Mary] We're gonna walk calmly.
We're gonna walk slowly.
We're gonna stay
with our partners.
-Okay. here we go.
-[Kevin] Yeah. Come on.
-What do you think. like. ten minutes?
-Uh. yeah. if we get a move on. yes.
But the traffic's getting really busy
out there. So the quicker. the better.
Okay. We have time.
Well. you know. ma'am.
I don't think you understand the
urgency of our situation here.
I recognize the urgency
of our situation.
And it's Mary. not "ma'am."
Hoods up if you have a hood!
If you have a backpack.
put it on top.
-[students clamoring. screaming]
-Okay! It's okay! It's okay! It's okay!
It's just a fire engine in the
sky! Use your backpacks. okay?
All right.
Find a seat on the bus. babe.
Quietly. calmly.
one single line.
Not quickly. take your time.
[Kevin] 963 to Base.
we're loading the
kids on the bus now.
[students chattering]
[Kevin] The signal's bad. I'll let
you know when we're clear. over.
Everybody. I want you to stay seated
and listen to everything Kevin says.
-Okay?
-W-Wait. wait. wait!
Alex! I need Alex!
-Alex? Alex. honey. your mom is here.
-Alex!
Okay. you have all your things?
-You gotta go. Okay.
-Oh. thank God.
Let's go. Let's go. Let's go.
[Mary] Okay. you are good to go.
[Kevin] Whoa. whoa. whoa.
Ma'am. ma'am. Whoa. whoa. whoa.
No. no. Y-You're coming. Yes.
No. No. [stammers]
I have to lock up.
No. no. no. no.
Y-You can't. I...
I'm gonna drive and drop. Okay?
I can't hang about and hold
any hands when I get there.
I've got my own family
I gotta get home to.
Okay? You gotta come.
I-I don't think he can do this by
himself. I have to go with him.
-[Kevin] Pipe down!
-It's fine.
[stutters] I'll get a ride
from one of the teachers there.
-Here. take the evac for HQ.
-You okay to lock up alone?
-Yeah.
-All right. I'm here. I'm here.
-I'm coming.
-[students cheering]
-We're good.
-[Kevin] Hang on.
[Mary] We got on the bus.
We're gonna be there.
It's gonna take ten minutes.
Did you see those fire engines?
Okay. um. here is the
school's evac route.
We are... the East line. so we're
gonna stay on Pentz all the way down.
and then cut a right on Pearson
to get us to Paradise Elementary.
[stutters] I don't-I don't think
it's a good idea. L-Look at it.
[stutters] T-There's a better
way out than Pentz right.
Okay. but that's the plan. So
we're gonna stick to the plan.
Whatever you say. teach.
-[helicopter whirring]
-[chattering on radio]
It's total gridlock. Look how
tight those roads are right now.
It's gotta be at least 15 miles
of traffic trying to get to Chico.
[pilot] Chief. we're
arriving at the fairgrounds.
[chief] Copy that.
I'm issuing a mandatory
evacuation on the whole town.
All zones. Effective
immediately.
Chief. you can't do
it. It'll be chaos.
We're talking 26.000 people.
If you get everyone
moving out of town.
you're never gonna
get your engines in.
You're not listening. The
fire's coming across the canyon.
I've seen it with my own
eyes. It's moving fast.
Here's the choice.
bust the system or play by
the book and everybody dies.
You want that on
your conscience?
[chattering]
Chief. we got the team
ordered early for ya.
-Copy.
-All right.
Hey. Chief. Chief.
Mark Rogers of PG&E.
I have a team here from
headquarters. We're available.
Just get the power off in the town.
and we'll take care of the rest.
-Yeah.
-[firefighter] Okay. listen.
We gotta give the chief some space.
We will come to you in a second.
Just... No. just wanted to say
we're available if you need us.
Issue mandatory evac
order for the entire town.
[firefighter] Copy.
Chief. Oroville. Camp Ops.
Base to 179. 179. Are you clear?
Are you out of East Paradise?
-[bus driver] 179. We're out.
-[Ruby] Great. great.
Who's left?
963 is the only one left.
That's all.
Base to 963.
Base to 963. are you
out of East Paradise?
[static on radio]
[horns honking]
[Kevin] 963 to Base.
[sighs] Do you read?
[Mary] Don't be scared. The-The fire
trucks are responding to the fire.
-They're doing their job.
-[Kevin] Anybody. 963 to Base.
-They're keeping us safe.
-[Kevin] Can anybody hear me?
Okay? We are on Pentz. It
is backed up going nowhere.
963. come in please.
Can you try his mobile?
Why does he have to be the last
bus out of there? I swear to God.
[Kevin] 963 to
Base. do you read?
Let me know if you're
getting this. Over.
Do you have any safety
protocols on this bus?
[Kevin] Yep. You got this.
and you got that.
Great. Yeah. That'll
make all the difference.
[siren wailing]
So you're new here?
No. I just came back
a few months ago.
Grew up here.
Oh. What's that like?
[groans] Not where I
thought I'd be at 44.
How long do you think
this is gonna take?
Hard to tell.
If we'd have left the school on time.
you wouldn't have slow played me.
it would have taken about ten minutes.
but now it's looking like 20-30.
Guess we'll get there when
we get there. Okay. kiddies.
Let's. um. raise some of these
windows so the smoke doesn't get in.
-[sirens wailing]
-[Ruby] Hi. Is this fire command?
This is Ruby Bishop at PUSD. I've
lost all radio communication.
and I have a lost bus.
It's number 963. and it's over
somewhere in East Paradise.
Can you let me know if
your engines see him?
Thank you.
Okay. okay. Okay. uh...
963. do you read?
[static on radio]
Kevin? Can you... Can you
hear me? This is Base.
[static on radio]
[Mary] Honey. let's. um...
move this up so
smoke doesn't get in.
-What's your name?
-Benjamin.
Benjamin. and you're in Miss Kristy's
class? That's right. I remember that.
[student] Miss Mary.
there's another window.
[Mary stammers] Yes.
Let's get that one.
Screw this.
-[students screaming]
-Kevin!
What are you doing? The
plan is to stay on Pentz!
Turning over to Clark. It runs parallel.
It's bound to be moving better.
[Mary] But that's not the plan.
-The plan is to stay on Pentz.
-Screw the plan. teach.
You know what?
Hey. I could stay here
in the middle of the traffic
jam if that's what you want.
-Don't stop now. obviously.
-Want me to stay here?
No shit. Let me drive.
-What the hell is your problem?
-Look. you see that fire?
It's like the fucking
Fourth of July. okay?
I'd sit down if I were you.
I'm about to take a hard left.
-Bunch down. everybody!
-[Mary] Hold on!
[students screaming]
Oh. my God! Oh. my
God! Hold on. kids!
-Oh. my God! Kevin!
-[fire truck horn blares]
-[Kevin yells]
-Hold on!
-[students clamoring]
-Jesus. Jesus Christ.
-[Kevin] We're clear.
-[Mary] Is everyone okay?
[students chattering]
We're okay. Traffic is moving.
Can you please ask before you
do something like that again?
You wanna get there quicker
or you wanna go by the book?
We have to be responsible.
Yep. and I think that means getting these
kids to their parents as soon as possible.
Don't you?
[sighs]
[inhales sharply]
-I'm not getting anything.
-Kevin. come in please.
[alarm beeps]
[electronic voice] This is a code red
alert. Evacuate all zones immediately.
[technician] Ruby. we gotta
go. I gotta get the power off.
-[Ruby] I know.
-I'm getting my guys outta here.
[Ruby] Okay. okay. Uh.
take my keys. Okay?
963. do you read?
[siren wailing]
[sighs]
So. what about you?
You always lived here?
[sighs] Yeah. Born and raised.
Never was really my speed.
Then why'd you come back?
My dad died a few months ago.
-Sorry.
-[Kevin] Nah. it's fine.
We weren't close.
So you staying?
-[siren wailing]
-For now.
What about you? Got family?
Yeah.
Married 19 years.
A Paradise poster
family too. huh?
[scoffs] Yeah.
-One kid.
-[Kevin] Hmm.
Jake. He's 15.
I was gonna go get him. but...
[sighs] I didn't realize. Sorry.
[Mary] It's fine.
My sister will
have gone for him.
His dad's out of town.
[sighs]
It'll be fine.
We're gonna drop the kids off.
and then I'll go find him.
-All right. How're we doing?
-[student 1] Are we gonna be okay?
[Mary] Yes. We're
gonna be okay. sweetie.
[student 2] Are our pets okay?
[student 3] When will
we see our parents?
[Mary] We'll see
them there. yeah?
We're just trying to get you to
safety as soon as we can. okay?
-[cries]
-Yes. sweetie?
[student 4] When are
we going to be there?
[Mary] We're gonna be there
as soon as we can. okay?
You okay. sweetie?
Mm-hmm.
Do you want to sit up
front with somebody else.
or do you want to
be by yourself?
[Ruby] Kevin. if you can hear me.
they're evacuating the whole town.
and emergency services are
mustering 15 miles away
-at Chico Fairgrounds where it's safe.
-[horn honking]
Do not drop those kids off.
Just take 'em and
come to Chico. Okay?
[honking continues]
[technician] Ruby. we're
outta time. We gotta go.
-I gotta get my guys out of here.
-Okay!
Ruby!
[honking continues]
Kevin. if you can hear me. I
will see you in Chico. okay?
Be careful. Base clear.
[honking continues]
[worker] Come on!
[firefighter] Chief. the fire's
spreading fast through East Paradise.
And I just got word
from Division Hotel.
You got a working fire in the cardiology
wing at Feather River Hospital.
It's well established
in the attic.
You got about 15 to 20 patients
that are outside right now.
We're working on getting
them outta there.
Do whatever you can in there
and save the hospital. okay?
Get me Butte medics. and
tell them we need help.
Chief. Air Attack has
grounded all aircraft.
Now. I'll get you an
update as soon as I can.
but right now nothing
goes in the air.
-Nothing.
-Goddamn it.
Where are we with the evacuation
route? How's this traffic moving?
[firefighter 2] You can see now
the fires across from Clark Road.
they're getting
impacted by fire.
Pentz Road is gridlocked.
Skyway is still open.
It's moving slow.
But what about all
these abandoned cars?
We're having major
access issues.
I want any vehicle blocking
traffic pushed off the road.
Okay? Get dozers in
there if you have to.
[firefighter 2] Got it.
[chief] We can't lose
those four routes out.
We lose those. it's game over.
-Hey. everybody! Listen up! Listen up!
-Everybody. quiet!
[chief] This is no
longer a wild land fire.
This is burning home to home.
This is a town fire.
This is a mass
casualty incident.
That's what we're dealing with.
So stay on with your people.
and do the best you can.
-Copy. Chief.
-[firefighter 3] Copy that.
[horns honking]
[students chattering]
Hey! What's the holdup?
Got a roadblock up ahead!
The freeway's jammed.
Shit!
[students chattering]
[horn honks]
Come on.
[Mary] Where do
you need to get to?
-After we drop off the kids.
-Magalia.
My son's up there
with his grandma.
I told them I'd be
coming straight home.
Well. they'll get the
evacuation alerts.
Won't they?
You signed up for them. right?
I...
You know. I-I kept
getting the noti...
[sighs] ...notifications
from the town hall
and I just kept putting it off.
Well. can his grandma drive?
Nope.
[horn honks]
[student 1] Miss Mary. help.
[student 2] Miss Mary. there's
smoke coming from that house.
[students chattering. screaming]
Fire on the left.
-Fire on the left. Bunch down.
-[Mary] Stay away from the windows.
Everybody stay off the windows.
[horn honking]
Hey.
Just let me in!
Come on!
Buddy. I got kids on the bus.
[Mary] Stay calm. Kevin's
trying to get us through.
Mary. take a seat.
-What? Why?
-Take a seat. I need you to drive.
-I need you to drive.
-I don't know how.
I've gotta clear traffic in the left
lane. I need you to take over the bus.
It's easy. Okay?
You put your foot on the brake.
when I say come. hit the gas.
It's easy. Okay? Yes.
you do. Hold the brake.
-Okay.
-When I say. "Come on." come on.
-Okay?
-Okay.
Stay seated.
Where's Kevin?
[officer] Back it up.
Back this truck up. We gotta
get this fire engine in.
-Let's go. Keep 'em going!
-Hey. hey. hey. What's going on?
-What're you doing? What's the plan?
-We got people trapped on Pentz.
Those people got priority.
-The main fire's over there.
-See the school bus?
I have 22 kids on that bus. I gotta
get them to their parents. okay?
[student] Where's Kevin?
[Kevin] I need you to hold traffic
here so we can come through.
I gotta clear this traffic to
let the fire truck through.
Get on the radio and call
fuckin' backup. will you?
Our comms are down. They've been
down for about 40 minutes or so.
Get back in your car. We'll
get you through when we can.
Get back in your car. sir.
-Get back in your car.
-[Kevin] Go left.
We gotta get the fire truck
and this bus through first.
Go! Go!
Go. go. go! Go. go. go!
Hold it!
-Go!
-[driver yelling]
Come on.
-[students clamoring]
-[horns honking]
Okay.
Let the fire truck
and the bus through!
Come on. go. go. go. go!
Yes.
Go! Go!
[students clamoring]
Come on. Come on!
I-I don't want to hit you.
Are we gonna be okay?
Come on.
[siren wailing]
[Mary breathes heavily]
Come on!
[pants] Holy shit.
[Kevin] Yes!
[Mary] We did it.
We made it through.
[students cheering]
What was wrong?
Radios are down. It's chaos.
A minute out. minute out.
Minute out! Are we ready?
963. We are one minute out from
drop-off. One minute out from drop-off.
Nice driving.
Thanks. Not so bad yourself.
[exhales]
You could always
be a traffic cop
if you're looking
for a fresh start.
I'd take a hard pass on that.
[chuckles]
[sighs]
Okay. kids. You can get your things
ready. Be ready to get off the bus.
I'm gonna get you to your
parents as quickly as we can.
[students clamoring]
-[student 1] Our parents...
-[student 2] The school's...
-[student 3] Oh. my God.
-[student 4] No! Where are they?
-[Kevin] No. no. no. no. no. No. no.
-[Mary] Where are they?
[students clamoring]
[Kevin] Oh. shit!
I want my mom. [cries]
I'll go see if anybody's there.
Hello!
[Kevin grunts]
[Kevin coughing]
[pants]
[Mary] They're...
They're not here.
There's no one here.
I don't know why they
didn't warn us or...
What do we do?
I don't know.
What... [sighs]
We gotta get outta here. We
gotta get these kids out of here.
Try to get them down to the
main evac center in Chico.
And then we can come
back for our kids.
[student] Miss Mary!
I'm coming. I'm coming.
[exhales sharply]
Sit down.
-[student 2] Ava needs you.
-What's wrong with Ava?
[student 2] She won't
come from under her seat.
-What? She's on the floor?
-Yeah. she needs you.
-Why? What's wrong with her?
-She won't get up!
-She's scared.
-[Mary] Ava. Honey. no.
[Ava sniffles]
[stammers] What are
you doing down there?
[Ava breathing shakily]
-Are you okay?
-[whimpers]
No?
-It's all a little bit scary.
-[Kevin] Okay.
-Mary. are we good?
-[Mary] Yeah. Good to go.
Okay.
Are you scared?
-Yeah. [sniffles]
-[Mary] Yeah.
I know.
I'm scared too.
Can I give you a hug?
[Ava] Mm-hmm. [sniffles]
[Mary] There you go. Come on.
Be as brave as you can be.
[chattering on radio]
[firefighters yelling]
[siren wailing]
Chief. you've got 27.000
people in Paradise.
12.000 in Magalia.
You've got maybe 8.000
people evacuated.
which means you've got 30.000 people
left in the footprint of the fire.
Finney. come here a second.
Update on the infrastructure.
How we doing with that?
So. infrastructure. Chief. we got
multiple schools in the town here.
We have two that are being impacted
immediately along-along Pentz road.
I also have a report that a school
bus came out of Ponderosa Elementary
with 22 kids on it. It's
unaccounted for right now. but...
Keep me updated on that.
We also have multiple
gas stations.
We have two propane facilities.
One in Skyway in between Pentz and
Clark and another one in Magalia.
-Can you shut them down?
-I'll work on it.
[firefighter] Part of the evacuation
problem. power lines are coming down.
They cannot get across the road.
Firefighters are cutting them right now to
open it up. but we're getting reports...
Where's PG&E?
[firefighter] We're getting
reports of active power lines.
-[firefighter 2] PG&E.
-Yeah.
-[chief] I thought the power was off.
-It is.
Tell them what's going on.
Why is your power on?
It's... Look. we're
working on it.
[firefighter] We got civilians
driving across power lines.
-We got firefighters cutting lines...
-I understand.
-...and lines are still arcing?
-You told me the power was off.
-Look. All the automatic power is off.
Thereafter it's manual
switches that have to be done.
-We're working as fast as we can.
-I don't give a shit.
-I understand.
-Do you know what's going on here?
Shut the fucking power off!
-Okay.
-What the fuck is wrong with you?
I've got firefighters in there!
There's 30.000 people in there!
[horns honking]
[Mary] What the hell
are we gonna do?
[Kevin] The fire's behind us.
We gotta stay ahead of it
and stay due southwest.
That clear patch of
sky. that's our way out.
We stay out of the fire. and we
head down to Chico from there.
Um. Pentz and-and Clark are out.
-so that leaves Neal and Skyway.
-Yeah. Yeah.
[Kevin] Yeah.
[Mary] Neal is the furthest
away. but maybe that's good.
Maybe there's less
traffic there.
[Kevin] But you have to take
Roe Road to get to Neal.
It's-It's narrow. and it's
full of 180 degree turns.
It's-it's not built
for a 35.000 pound bus.
We'd be trapped down
there. There's no way out.
-That really just leaves us Skyway.
-Skyway. Right.
-It's-It's wide. four lanes. straight.
-Yeah.
-Let's try Skyway. Okay.
-Skyway.
You don't know where
they are. do you?
[Mary] What. honey?
Our parents.
You don't know where they are.
No. honey. we don't. but
we're gonna find them.
We're gonna find their
parents. right. Kevin?
Yeah. Yeah. we're
gonna find them. Yeah.
I need you to take
your seat. sweetie.
You wanna sit down up here?
-Have a seat.
-[Mary] Here.
Yeah. this is fine.
What's your name?
Toby.
Your parents work out of town?
My mom does.
I don't see my dad.
I'll tell you what. Toby. We're
gonna get you back to your mom.
You hear me? We're gonna
get you back to your mom.
We're gonna get you back to your son.
and we're gonna get me back to mine.
That's what's going to happen.
Okay?
Okay.
[firefighter] So. Chief. the fire is
spreading through most of Paradise.
both business and
residential areas.
and we're getting reports of
significant structure loss.
and Air Attack is still
grounded with no ETA.
-Copy that.
-Hey. Chief.
I've-I've checked
in with division.
Last report of that bus was coming
down Clark Road south of Elliott. Okay?
I just got word
from Division Hotel
that Paradise Elementary
is well involved in fire.
They're not there.
[Kevin] Mary. can
you see these cables?
-Yeah.
-[Kevin] All right.
[explosions]
-[Mary] Oh. my God. Watch out.
-[students screaming]
Got it. Got it. Got it.
[horn honks]
-[yells]
-[Mary] Kevin. on the right! Kevin!
Power line on the right!
[people screaming]
[students screaming]
-[Kevin] The whole road's coming down.
-Oh. my God. [pants]
It's falling! It's falling!
Watch out! Watch out!
-[screams]
-Oh. my God.
[students screaming]
[Kevin] Going left!
It's gonna cut
through to Skyway.
We can make it.
It's just down here.
[Mary] Kids. hold on!
Hold onto something!
-Hang on!
-Oh. my God.
[Kevin] Shit!
[sirens wailing]
[firefighter 1
speaks indistinctly]
[firefighter 2] Keep it in
check! Back it up! Come on back!
[clamoring]
[inhales sharply] We're blocked.
We're totally blocked in.
We gotta get off. find a way to Roe.
and try to make a way out on Neal.
It's our only chance right now.
-How are we gonna get out of here?
-Look for a way off. Left or right.
I'm looking. I'm looking.
I don't see anything. There's no way
out. I don't see... It's everywhere.
It's all around us. How are
we gonna get out of here?
Oh. my God!
[screaming]
Look straight ahead.
-Don't look at that.
-[Kevin] Straight ahead!
Get out the fucking car!
[clamoring]
Kevin. there's looters.
-Open up. Let me in!
-Get off the windows!
Stay away from the windows!
-Down! Get down!
-[Kevin] Stay away from the windows!
[grunts] Give us the bus!
[grunts]
-Mary!
-[looter grunts] Open it!
He has a gun!
Kevin. he has a gun!
[looter] Open it!
-[grunts]
-Down! Duck. I said duck.
Open the door! [grunts]
-[Mary] We have to get out of here.
-[looter grunts]
We have to get out of here.
On the left. On the left.
Kevin. there's a gap.
Kevin. there's a gap. Go left.
Left. Go. go. go. go.
It's closing. It's closing.
[Kevin] We're through.
We're through.
[sighs]
-[sirens wailing]
-[clamoring]
[officer] Stay with
your family. please.
This is the safe area. sir.
We need you to stay here...
-Let's go. Let's go.
-[person] That's my daughter.
-[firefighter 1] Out of the way.
-[firefighter 2] Watch your back.
-Go!
-Move!
[Ruby] Just keep going. Just
keep going. Just keep going.
Whoa. whoa. Hold on.
[Ruby] I'm with the. uh.
Paradise Unified School District.
-Where are you from?
-Straight up.
[Ruby] Thank you. That's
where the busses are.
Okay. Thank you.
Just keep going.
This is the... Yeah. there
they are. There they are.
Let me out. Let me
out. Let me out.
-Cesar?
-[Cesar] Ruby.
Cesar. You heard any news?
-Nothing.
-963's not here?
[Cesar] Hasn't made it back yet.
Shit. [sighs]
[colleague] Ruby.
the parents are here.
Okay. Okay. Okay.
[students sobbing]
[Kevin] 963 to Base. 963
to Base. Do you read?
[static on radio]
-Miss Mary. I don't have any water left.
-963 to all vehicles.
-Do you read? Any vehicles. do you read?
-I'm thirsty. I'm way too hot.
Okay. Okay.
[sighs] Here. honey.
Get a folder or a... a
notebook or something...
Hey. listen. we just got
off Skyway. It was a no-go.
Here. Use it like this.
We're gonna try and-and-and
make our way out through Neal.
Stay out of the fire. Get out
that way. It's our only shot.
Miss Mary. we really
need some water.
Hang in there. sweetie.
I know. It's really hot.
Kevin. the kids
are not gonna last.
They need water. They're
hot. and they're thirsty.
[students screaming]
-[student 1] What's happening?
-[student 2] What is that?
[Mary] What the hell is that?
[student 3] I can't breathe.
It's coming through the vents.
[students coughing]
The smoke. The smoke is getting
in. Kevin. the smoke is coming in.
It's coming through the AC.
[Mary] Then turn it off.
It's gonna make the
heat worse. but okay.
We have to try something.
[AC powering down]
[Kevin] Okay. it's off. Off.
We must be inside
the smoke column.
-[pants] Watch out.
-Yeah. Yeah. I see it. I see it.
[Kevin] Meadow Creek Park.
Yeah. Yeah. There's...
There's a back exit.
[Mary] What?
I worked here one
summer as a kid.
It leads out to Roe Road.
and then we can get over to
Neal. and then we're out. Okay?
-[Mary] Yes. yes. yes. yes. yes.
-Yes.
Miss. Ma'am.
-Yeah?
-There's something wrong with Shannon.
-She needs your help.
-She's wheezing a little bit.
-[Shannon wheezing]
-[Mary] What's wrong. honey?
-Okay. Okay. Don't talk. Don't talk.
-[breathing heavily]
Just breathe slowly. okay? Slowly.
Try to slow down your breathing.
Okay. You just need
to drink some water.
Um. can everybody just
look in their backpack
and make sure you don't have.
like. a juice box or something?
Kevin. we... we have to find
water or she's gonna stroke out.
We have to get off the bus now.
-Right there. Right there.
-Yep. yep.
-[Mary] Yes. Yes. Okay.
[Kevin] Okay. We can't stop
for long. I'll be two minutes.
[Mary] No. no. no. no. no. no.
You need to stay on the bus.
If the fire comes. you
have to drive them.
Let me go. I can do it. Two
minutes. I'll be right back.
I can do it.
[student] Miss Mary.
where are you going?
[student 2] Miss Mary.
Miss Mary. come back.
[grunts. coughs]
-[students crying]
-[student 3] Where did Mary go?
Shit.
[grunts]
[chiming]
[student 4] Do you know
where Miss Mary is?
[Kevin] She... She just
went to look for some water.
Just-Just give her a minute.
[student 1] Please
come back. Miss Mary.
[student 2] Where is she going?
[student 3] I can't see her.
[coughing]
[Mary coughs]
[Mary] Come on.
Come on.
[grunting]
[student] Come back.
[students coughing. crying]
[horn honking]
[honking continues]
[Mary] Yes. Yes.
[grunts. pants] Got it.
Oh. my God. Got it.
Mary!
[students clamoring]
[Mary panting. groaning]
[students scream]
Mary!
[crying]
-Mary!
-[student 1] What do we do now?
-[explosion]
-[screams]
-Mary!
-[Mary panting] I'm coming!
I'm coming! [panting]
-Go. go. go. go.
-[Mary] Help me. Help me.
Get the water. Get the water.
[student 2] Miss Mary's here.
[panting]
[door creaks. closes]
-[Mary] Okay.
-You okay?
I'm okay. I'm okay. I'm okay.
-[engine revving]
-[students screaming]
[sniffles]
[exhales deeply]
Can somebody get this
water to Shannon?
-[yells]
-Oh. my God!
[grunts]
[Mary] Duck! Down!
Cover your heads!
-[yells]
-[students scream]
-Shit!
-[Mary] Oh. my God!
[groans]
Everybody. hold on! Stay
away from the windows.
Everyone. hold on!
Oh. my God. We gotta go
right. That's the way out.
-[screams]
-[Mary] Oh. my God!
[Kevin] Hold on!
Okay. Stay down. Stay down.
On the right. On the
right. On the right.
-That burnt building on the right.
-[screams]
This is the way out.
[pants] That's it.
Here it is. This is the
exit. This takes us to Roe.
[Ruby] Hello. everyone.
If I could get y'all in.
Uh. my name is Ruby Bishop.
I am the school's director
of transportation.
and I just wanna
give you an update.
I know y'all are worried.
but I want you to know first and foremost
that your children were evacuated
from Ponderosa Elementary
earlier this morning. Okay?
[parent] When will we know more?
Unfortunately. shortly
after leaving the school.
the fire destroyed our
radio communication.
So we have not had contact with
the bus since it left Ponderosa.
Wait. you don't
know where they are?
[Ruby] All I know is that they're
probably somewhere over in East Paradise.
[parent 2] East
Paradise is on fire!
I know. but I want you to know
that both police and fire command
are looking for them
out there. okay?
They're doing their best.
but you must know that your
children are on the bus
with a driver and a
teacher named Mary Ludwig.
-Some of you may know Mrs. Ludwig?
-[parents murmuring]
-Okay.
-Which... Which driver is it?
Yes. His-His name is Kevin McKay.
He's a new driver to our district.
-[parents 3] New driver?
-[Ruby] Listen...
-Everybody. please.
-[parents clamoring]
Please. I know.
I know this is really
difficult news.
-He's a good driver.
-[Ruby] Kevin McKay.
I can vouch for Kevin McKay.
as can all of my drivers.
He is a good man. and he is
gonna do everything he can.
You have to trust him.
I trust him. and right now he is
all we have got out there. Okay?
[electricity crackling]
[Kevin] This is it.
[panting] This is Roe Road.
Fire's behind us.
Okay. a couple of miles on this
should get us out towards Neal.
Okay.
[Mary] Okay.
Rocks on the right.
Watch your left.
-There's a drop-off.
-[student 1] I'm scared.
[Mary] We're gonna
be okay. guys.
You don't need to worry. We're
gonna get through this. okay?
[student 2] Watch out.
[Kevin] Mary.
[stammers] What do
I have over there?
[stammers] Four feet?
[Mary] Two. [sighs]
Maybe two and a half.
[pants]
[firefighter] Chief. our
fire in Butte Creek Canyon
and our fire in the west
branch have merged in Paradise.
It's burning aligned
with the wind.
burning to the southwest
portion of Paradise.
The only area that
hasn't burned.
and the fire is heading in this
direction. is this area right here.
Foster Road. Roe Road.
Hey. these are tight roads.
A lot of structures in
there. It's all downhill.
You've got numerous spot fires
being reported down here already.
This area's gonna be fully
engulfed in fire very soon.
We have got zero resources
to put down here.
They're all engaged up here.
Whatever's down here.
they're gonna have to figure out for
themselves how to get out of Paradise.
We've got nothing to give
'em. Absolutely nothing.
[students coughing]
[student 1] Miss Mary.
[student 2] What are
they doing over there?
[Mary] Who are those people?
-[coughing]
-What are they doing?
Why are they going
back towards the fire?
[person] Here! Here!
-[person 2] Yo! Hey! Hey! Stop! Stop!
-[students clamoring]
[Kevin] No. no. no. no.
Come around this side.
[stammers] Is there
a way out down there?
[person 2] That fire's
burning across the ridge.
-People are dying down there.
-We got out on foot.
Do not go that way. The trailer
park. everything is burning.
Everything. There's no way out.
-What the hell are we gonna do?
-I-I just need to get to Neal Road.
No. you can't go to
Neal Road. It's on fire.
You don't want these kids
to see what we just saw.
Trust me.
Do not go that way.
Hey. we're gonna
take our chances.
Shit. [sighs]
[person 3] Good luck.
[engine stops]
What do we do?
[student 1] Why have we stopped?
-[student 2] No. keep going.
-I wanna go home.
Okay. Everyone. we just need
to stay quiet and calm. please.
And Kevin and I. we'll.
uh. figure this out.
[student 3] We need
to keep moving.
Okay. I'm gonna go have a look.
Check this ridge and this ridge.
Get the kids ready in case we have
to take them off the bus. okay?
[Mary] Okay.
[student 4] Kevin. what
are you doing? Don't go.
-Okay. Okay.
-[students clamoring]
[panting]
[Mary] Okay. Kids. this is
what I need for us to do.
I need us to stay quiet.
I need us to stay calm.
Kevin is going to check if it's
okay for us to get off the bus.
-In the meantime...
-[coughs]
...I want you to grab your backpack
and make a line in the aisle.
Slowly. quietly. as
calmly as you can. please.
[sighs]
[panting]
[exhales deeply]
Come on.
[coughing]
[Mary] Okay. As soon as Kevin gets
back. we're gonna file off. okay?
[students] Yes. ma'am.
[Mary] We're gonna
stay really close.
You're gonna find someone's
hand to hold. okay?
Stay really. really close.
-[knocks on door]
-[student] Look. Kevin. he's back.
[Mary] There he is.
[Kevin pants] Get the
kids. Seat the kids.
-We're staying on the bus.
-Okay.
-Staying on the bus.
-Okay. Everybody. sit down.
-[student] Wait. Wait. What?
-Everybody. sit.
Miss Mary. I thought you
said we were gonna go.
I did. honey. But... [stammers]
...we're gonna stay on the bus.
Uh. Henry. you're...
Take a seat. We're gonna... Kevin
and I are gonna figure out what...
-What happened?
-We're surrounded.
-Oh. my God.
-There's nowhere to go.
What? No. No. no. no. That's
impossible. It's impossible.
-There's gotta be a way out. [stammers]
-Listen to me.
-We're here on Roe.
-Okay. Okay.
-[Kevin] This is Neal.
-Okay.
[Kevin] I saw it all
from the ridge. okay?
The fire's on all sides. It's
here. it's here. here and here.
-Oh. my God.
-We gotta st... We gotta stay here.
We gotta... We gotta
stay on the bus.
We're gonna stay on the bus.
No.
-[grunts] No. We...
-We're gonna stay on the bus.
No. We... No. No. No.
We could go out on foot.
Those other people.
they went out on foot.
-We could try on foot.
-No. No way.
They won't last two minutes
out there. There's no way.
They won't last... They
won't last two minutes.
[both panting]
Gotta stay.
What? What. we stay here?
We just...
What do you... [stammers] We're
just gonna wait? What do...
-Maybe... Maybe the fire doesn't...
-What if the fire comes. but we...
Maybe it does or maybe
it doesn't come. okay?
I d... I don't know.
All I do know is we are in the
one place where the fire is not.
And we're alive right now. And
we got a little bit of time.
Stay.
That's our only chance.
Are you sure?
Yes.
[whispers] But what
if the fire comes?
What if the fire comes. Kevin?
[panting]
Listen to me.
[stammers. sobs]
What do we do with the
kids if the fire comes?
We gotta stay on the bus.
Okay. [inhales shakily]
[whimpers]
-Okay?
-Okay. [sobs]
Okay.
We'll stay on the...
We'll stay on the bus.
[crying]
[students coughing]
[inhales deeply]
[sighs]
[breathing heavily]
[Kevin] Mary. hey.
I need your help.
We gotta buy some time.
I'm gonna cut my shirt up
into small pieces. All right?
What are you doing?
I'm gonna make some
filters for their mouths.
Wet them with some water.
It can soothe their throats.
Let's move the kids to the back of the
bus away from the... the air vents.
I'm gonna tape as many
vents as I can. okay?
Okay.
Chief. the water
supply is failing.
We've got no pressure
in the hydrants.
We are losing this thing.
Can I talk to you over
here for a second?
[Mary] So we're gonna
rest for a little bit.
and I wanna move you
to the back of the bus
so that you're further
away from the smoke. okay?
[student] Okay. Miss Mary.
Honey. can we move to the
back of the bus. all right?
Come on. this way.
That should help to keep
some of the smoke out. okay?
So we're getting reports of people
burning to death in their cars.
And we've got hundreds of people
running for their lives on foot.
[students coughing]
[Mary] Okay. girls. We're gonna
be here for a little while.
I want you to take this filter.
put it over your mouth and
your nose and breathe. okay?
[firefighter] If we don't play this
right. we're gonna wake up in the morning
to hundreds or. I don't know.
even thousands of fatalities.
Okay? So at this point.
we can do one thing.
We can fight fire or save lives.
We are out of time.
I want you to put it over your
mouth and your nose and breathe.
-It's gonna help with the smoke. okay?
-Okay.
-[Mary] Yeah? How are you doing. sweetie?
-How long are we staying here?
[Mary] Thank you for taking
care of her. sweetie.
Mmm.
[Mary] Ava. I want you to
put this over your mouth.
[chief] Okay. listen up.
Cease all firefighting.
Get with your
resources inside town
and tell them to save
lives wherever they can.
That's all we can do now.
[firefighter] Copy that. Chief.
[firefighters chattering]
[person coughs] Hurry up.
[coughs]
[students coughing]
[sniffs]
[sighs]
The windows are so hot.
-I have to warn the kids.
-No. no. no. I can do it.
-No. no. I can... I'm good. I can do it.
-I... I know... I know you can.
Rest for a second.
I... I can do it.
Okay. Thank you.
[Kevin] Hey. guys.
The walls and the windows are really
hot. so... so don't touch them.
Okay? I want you to come...
lean towards the aisle.
Here we go. Can you come
this way a little bit?
The floor's really hot too.
Let's do the. um...
What do you do at story time?
Let's go crisscross?
Apple sauce?
Say it with me.
-[students] Crisscross apple sauce.
-Crisscross.
That's it. that's it. That's
it. Good. Good job. buddy. Okay.
[student] Is it nighttime?
What's that. sweetie?
Is it nighttime?
No. no. no. It's not nighttime.
It's just... It's smoke. It's in
between us and the sunshine. Okay?
Are we gonna be okay? [whimpers]
Yeah. [sighs] We are
gonna be... Yes. we are.
And that smoke's gonna go away.
and the sun's gonna come back out.
Okay?
Toby. you okay?
I want my daddy.
Yeah.
Yeah. I know you do.
He knows you do too. Okay?
Listen.
He's... He's doing everything
he can to get to you.
Okay? And he's trying his best.
-Okay? Toby. look at me.
-[sniffles]
Okay?
[breathing heavily]
[Kevin sighs]
How much time do we have?
Another hour maybe.
Those filters won't
last much longer.
Maybe we should just
let them go to sleep.
It's better.
[inhales shakily] Then
if the fire comes...
-[Kevin] No. no. no. No. No. No.
-[cries]
We can't... We can't let
ourselves talk like that. Okay?
Okay.
[inhales sharply]
[water running. splashing]
[chief] Good afternoon.
I'm Chief Martinez.
[reporters clamoring]
At approximately 6:30
a.m. this morning.
a fire was reported near the Pulga
Bridge. eight miles east of Paradise.
The fire spread rapidly.
overwhelming our best
efforts to contain it.
And at approximately
8:30 a.m. this morning.
the fire entered the
town of Paradise.
Unfortunately. moments ago. I
was forced to give the order
to cease firefighting in Paradise
and focus solely on protecting life.
Right now. there's still
thousands of residents trapped
or attempting to flee the fire.
And while we are doing everything
we humanly can to assist them...
despite our best efforts.
this community is facing the
full force of the fire alone.
-[reporters murmuring]
-[shutters clicking]
So we ask for your patience.
and I'll hand it over to Sheriff Thomas.
who may have more information for you.
We have to get back
to work. Thank you.
[reporters clamoring]
I just wanna add one thing.
Every year the fires get bigger.
And there's more of them.
We're being damn fools.
That's the truth. Thank you.
-[reporters clamoring]
-[shutters clicking]
[students coughing. wheezing]
This is gonna sound
silly to you...
but I've only ever
left Paradise one time.
Oh.
How's that?
To go to Ohio.
Two weeks.
On my friend's farm.
And one time. Steven and I did
a weekend in San Francisco.
I thought that I'd be safe here.
Just stay in Paradise.
Stay with him. Follow the rules.
And nothing bad
could truly happen.
But that's no way
to live a life.
Hiding away.
[sighs] That's one thing I'd
change if we get out of here.
I'd take a trip.
[breathes shakily]
I'd take Jake to Legoland.
[sniffles]
Or Africa maybe. I don't know.
[sighs]
I would love to see elephants.
Animals at a watering hole.
Anything really. Just anything.
Before it's too late.
[chuckling]
[chuckles] Why are you laughing?
Ah.
I've spent my entire life
trying to escape Paradise.
and now for some reason all I
wanna do is make a go of it here.
Why did you wanna leave?
[Kevin] You know. when I first got
the call to go pick up the kids.
uh. I started to
think that maybe...
maybe I could earn a second chance
if I just got the kids out safe.
you know?
Except they don't always work
that way. Second chances.
[Mary] Why do you say that?
The last time I spoke to
my dad was 28 years ago.
I was 16. It was
Christmas Eve. And. uh...
We got into a fight.
Something about me not
finishing what I started.
Same kind of shit. same
fight it always was.
Anyway. he. uh...
He came at me. you know.
like he... like he usually had
and done so many times before.
And for whatever reason.
on this night. I snapped.
I went at him s... screaming and
swinging and next thing I knew.
I slammed the front door
and cursed his name.
Told him I never wanted
to see him again.
He then said. "I
wish you were dead."
First. it was pride. you know?
Then after a few years.
my life went to shit.
Turned to shame.
A few months ago. I was working
the night shift back in Reno.
And that's when I got the call.
It was my mom.
She said. "You know. Kevin.
your dad's real sick.
You need to come home."
Drove all night.
But I was too late.
He died that morning.
I was too late... as a son.
Now I'm too late as a father.
How many times my son's
reached out to me?
[crying]
And now it's too late.
I didn't show up.
[sniffles]
[Mary] It's not too late.
It's up to you.
-Fire!
-[gasps]
[students screaming]
Oh. shit.
[Mary] There's fire.
Oh. my God. Oh. my God.
-[student] Behind us.
-Fire in the back.
There's fire in the
back. I'll be right back.
Kevin! Kevin! Kevin. it's in the
back. It's in the back of the bus.
-There's fire.
-Here. Go. go. go. Okay.
Oh. God. [pants]
[students clamoring]
[Mary grunting]
Miss Mary!
[pants. grunts]
[Mary grunts]
-[pants]
-[pants] Where?
Here. here. here. here. Here.
[grunts]
[Mary] Shit!
It's out. It's out!
It's out. It's out.
[students clamoring]
-Kevin. we're out.
-[grunts]
We're out. It's out.
-The spray.
-Go back to the bus.
Go back to the bus.
Go back to the bus!
Where are you going?
-No! No! Kevin!
-[panting]
Shit.
Okay.
[Kevin grunting]
Look for fires. Look for fires.
[crying]
[screams]
Kevin!
[groans]
[students screaming]
Oh. my God. Oh. my God.
Kevin!
[breathes heavily]
[breathing heavily]
[Mary] Kevin!
-[horn honking]
-Come on!
[panting]
It's behind us.
We gotta drive through it.
Gotta drive through it.
-[Mary] Sit down. sit down!
-[engine sputters]
What's wrong?
-No.
-Ah! Come on.
-[Mary] No. no. no. no.
-Come on. come on!
[engine sputters]
-[Mary] What? No! No.
-[Kevin sighs]
Take the wheel.
-[student 1] Kevin. don't go.
-[student 2] Come back.
[strains]
[student 3] What's Kevin doing?
[pants]
[groaning]
Try! Try now!
[engine sputters]
Goddamn it!
[panting]
[Kevin yelling]
-Please. please. please.
-[students crying]
[Kevin grunts]
[grunting]
[Kevin] Try it! Try now!
-[engine starts]
-Yes!
Okay! Okay! Okay!
[breathes shakily]
[Mary] Go! Go. go. go!
-[breathes heavily]
-[engine revs]
Get down. Get down. We're
going through the fire.
[students screaming]
[grunts]
[panting]
[engine revs]
[screaming continues]
[panting]
Oh. God.
[students screaming]
[Kevin yells]
[yells]
[screams]
[students screaming]
[engine revs]
[yells]
[screaming continues]
I don't wanna die!
[screams]
[panting]
Miss Mary. is it over?
[breathes heavily] Oh. God.
[students crying]
[sighs]
[whimpers]
[panting]
[Mary] It's okay. It's okay.
Okay. Okay. We're okay.
[breathing heavily]
[siren wailing]
[first responders clamoring]
[crying]
[officer] Come on
through. Come on through.
This way. This way! Come on!
Come on through. Follow them.
[horn honks]
[parent 1] Oh. my God. [gasps]
-[parent 2] Is that the bus?
-[parent 1 sobs]
-It's them. It's them.
-[clamoring]
Oh. my God. Oh. my God.
Mom.
[students clamoring]
[parents clamoring]
[clamoring continues]
Hi!
What are you waiting
for? Let's go.
[students clamoring]
-[clamoring]
-[applause]
[cries]
[student 1] Dad!
[student 2] Come on. Toby.
Here's your dad. Right
here. Right here.
Thirteen. 14. 15.
16. 17. 18. 19.
[Kevin] Toby.
Good luck. buddy.
[Mary] Your mom's right there.
Toby! Toby! [laughs]
[chuckles]
[Mary] All right.
-Thank you.
-[Kevin] Thank you.
You did good. You
did really good.
You did too.
Send me a picture of
those elephants. huh?
[both chuckle]
-[parents applauding]
-[parent 1] Mary!
No. no. Your children are
amazing. They were so brave.
[parent 2] Thank you. Mary.
Kevin. Kevin. Kevin.
-[parent 3] Thank you. Kevin.
-[parent 4] Thank you.
Excuse me. Excuse me.
I didn't know if
you got my call.
[people clamoring. laughing]
-You okay?
-Yeah.
[Mary cries]
Hey. boss.
Time for maintenance.
[laughs] Yeah. I probably owe you
a little overtime too. you know?
[laughs]
All right. now.
-Kevin.
-Hey. sir. Hey. how are you?
Good job. Good job.
All right. Thank you. man.
[cries]
[chattering on radio]
[first responders clamoring]
[crowd clamoring]
Sir. I'm sorry...
I'm sorry. I've got to
help the next one. sir.
Ma'am. come up here. please.
Ma'am. what is the name
you're looking for?
-[elderly person] Miller.
-[aid worker] Miller.
Ma'am. there is a Miller.
-Go to the disaster relief tent...
-[gasps] Where's that?
-[whimpers]
-...and look for your family. okay?
-They're over there.
-Excuse me.
-Hi. there. Um. McKay.
-What name?
M-C-K-A-Y.
-All right.
-Gonna be a Sherry and Shaun.
[stammers] They would've
come in from Magalia.
Sir. I'm sorry. I
don't see that name.
We'll keep an eye out for them.
Thank you.
[aid worker] Hi. there.
[sirens wailing]
[first responders clamoring]
Ma?
-Ma.
-Oh!
Hey. You made it.
How... How'd you get out?
-My neighbor. Carl...
-Carl.
-...he came and got me...
-Carl got you?
-...and brought me here. Yes.
-[sighs]
Listen. Ma. Where's Shaun?
Where's Shaun. Ma?
He's with his mother.
He's happiest when
he's with her.
He's safe.
It's for the best. Okay?
Yeah.
It is.
[bird squawking]
[chattering on radio]
[car door closes]
Watch Online Movies and Series for FREE
www.osdb.link/lm